Dalton Valliere

718 W Kalamazoo Ave, Apt 2 Kalamazoo, MI 49007

edvallie@gmail.com (248) 787-0771

Summary

I am a full stack developer with a wide range of experience covering the entire software development life cycle. I have worked on many web applications from the design phase, through development, and into an administration and maintenance stage.

Front-End

- **Bootstrap**
- jQuery
- Javascript
- HTML5
- CSS
- Twig

Tools

- Web Servers Apache and nginx
- Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Git / Gitlab
- KVM / OpenVZ / Virsh
- iptables / ufw
- Wireshark / tcpdump

Back-End

- PHP
- Bash
- Symfony MVC
- Perl
- Python
- SQL
- strace
- OpenVPN
- Bind
- Elastix
- Zentyal
- Mediawiki
- AWS EC2, S3, EFS, RDS, ELB, Auto-Scaling, Cloudfront, Cloudwatch, Route 53

Professional Experience

Title-Check LLC, Kalamazoo MI

Position: Full Stack Developer

March 2013 - Current

- Converted web services to fully scalable AWS platform
- Migrated servers into a KVM based virtualized environment
- Re-wrote primary customer facing website from scratch in Symfony2 MVC
- Object-Oriented PHP web development and document generation
- Setup documentation platform and started initiative to document all of our regular IT and development processes
- Developed in-house document retrieval API
- Managed various networking infrastructure(DNS, DHCP, Routing, VPN, etc)
- Designed normalized database schemas to support our custom applications
- RESTful API development
- Designed and developed in-house escrow management system

Kaufman Financial Group, Farmington Hills MI

Position: Helpdesk Technician

- Supported more than 1,000 users in Citrix environment

Created and managed MDT imaging process

January 2012 - March 2013

Western Michigan University - CS Department, Kalamazoo MI

Position: Systems Administrator

December 2006 - September 2008, September 2010 - May 2011

- Provided programming support for CS students
- Used Bash scripting to automate backup and logging processes
- Managed MSDN software distribution for Computer Science faculty and students
- Hosted and maintained distribution mirrors for Ubuntu, MSDN, Gentoo, Knoppix, Sabayon, Cygwin, CentOS and Blastwave

Kellogg Company, Battle Creek MI

Position: IT Intern - CRM Team

June 2009 – September 2010

- Development inside a customized SAP CRM Module with ABAP
- Oracle database management with TOAD
- Responsible for development of Access DuPage website, part of a community intern project
- Participated in testing systems for Program GO!, a full-scale implementation of the SAP HR module
- Project manager for the 2010 Kellogg's summer IT internship project

Western Michigan University – EUP, Kalamazoo MI

Position: LAN Specialist

August 2008 - June 2009

- Supported Western Michigan University faculty with laptop swap-out initiative
- Deployed and maintained Debian based servers

Education

Western Michigan University, Haworth College of Business

Major: Computer Information Systems

Minor: General Business

Volunteer & Other Activities

- President, Computer Club at Western Michigan University
- Founder and team leader of the Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition Team at Western Michigan University
- Business Technology Network at Western Michigan University member
- Kalamazoo Area Runners member
- CCNA Networking Courses
- Volunteered at Friendship Village Retirement Community teaching computer skills
- Managed and organized large-scale LAN parties on behalf of the Computer Club